ELIA NIKOLAOU

London, UK • +447778401360 • elia.nikolaou.23@gmail.com

CANDIDATE PROFILE

A postgraduate Information Security student, intrigued by technology and its potential to improve human life and experience. Strongly believe in working hard and adhering to the habit of setting targets and working towards achieving them.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON, London, UK

MSc Information Security

2022 - Present

- Modules: Information Security Management, People and Security, Malware, Cryptocurrencies, Computer Security, Cryptography
- Final Project: Improving Drand's distributed key generation protocol

UNIVERSITY OF CYPRUS - DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, Cyprus

BSc Computer Science (GPA: 8.12/10)

2018 - 2022

Member of winning Cypriot team at Huawei Seeds for the Future programme.

Represented the University at Huawei Talent Summit, Finland 2021

Final Year Modules: Software Analysis and Web Technologies

Dissertation: User-Friendly Generator For Privacy Policies

LATSIA LYCEUM, Latsia, Nicosia, Cyprus

Apolytirion (GPA: 18.67 - Excellent)

2015 - 2018

Core Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Design & Technology, Informatics Certificates of Academic Excellence awarded for all academic years Represented the School at the European Parliament, Euroscola 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TEACHING ASSISTANT - UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

London, UK

TA for "Introduction to Python" module

January 2023 - May 2023

COGNITIVE UX

Nicosia - Cyprus

Software Engineer Intern

July 2022 - December 2022

- Developed different front-end applications and assisted in the development of a project funded by the European Union.
- Designed codes for deliverables and company software products and solutions.

KIOS RESEARCH AND INNOVATION CENTRE OF EXCELLENCE

University of Cyprus, Nicosia - Cyprus

Special Scientist Intern

October 2021 - February 2022

Provided support with collecting and processing important data, essential for the continuation of projects.

ERNST & YOUNG - EY

Nicosia - Cyprus

Summer Intern (It Audit Team)

July 2021 - August 2021

- Prepared essential real information records and audits subject to IT audit.
- Undertook a variety of training related to various topics such as privacy, GDPR, cyberattacks, and IT audit...

KPMG

Nicosia - Cyprus

Summer Intern (Digital Innovation Team)

June 2021 - July 2021

- Presented a business game idea to potential investors with a team formed of 7 interns, resulted winning the challenge.
- Employed machine learning algorithms to extract results for a project, with the purpose to find the different relationships between some given products produced by a client.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Languages: Greek (Native), English (IELTS: 8)
- IT/Programming Skills: C, C++, C# Java, Python, Bash, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML, Docker, Microsoft Office Applications (ECDL certificate)
- Object-Oriented Programming, Machine Learning

ACTIVITIES

• Scouting: Member of the 297 Troop of Latsia (Cyprus Scouts Association), Current position: Leader. Scouting Award of Democracy of the Republic of Cyprus in 2018 (2007-Present)